Joshua Robins

E-mail: joshuazrobins@gmail.com

Phone: (818) 257-0963

Summary

Product leader with 2-3 years of experience strategically building and managing software applications using lean / agile principles, with an emphasis on user-centered design. A technologist at heart, a creative problem-solver, and a servant leader with experience leading cross-functional teams.

• Co-founded the Food Oasis LA nonprofit in 2016 and led its consumer-facing application. Orchestrated its acquisition to Youth Policy Institute in 2018.

Experience

LA Counts

Los Angeles, CA May 2018 – present

(25 hrs/wk)

Associate Project Manager / Product Manager

- Drove adoption of new project management tools and overhauled its Google Analytics setup to report more thoughtful metrics and data insights.
- Led the product team through design strategy and design sprints, handing off wireframes and high-fidelity mockups to developers.
- Conducted user testing sessions, gathering feedback and insights to drive informed decisions in each iteration of the design.
- Supported senior leadership in running weekly sync-ups with our developers, prioritizing features, and organizing the product roadmap / backlog.
- Engaged with external partners and stakeholders across government agencies, nonprofits, and universities.

Food Oasis LA

Los Angeles, CA May 2016 – Jan 2018 (20 hrs/wk)

Product Manager / Co-founder

- Led the shaping and defining of our shared product vision: To address the lack of food security and to help people living in America's largest food desert (Los Angeles County).
- Led a diverse group of volunteers to design and build an MVP within 4 months. Delivered 2 months ahead of schedule (6-month objective).
- Conducted weekly user interviews and testing sessions to ensure a user-centered focus in each sprint.
- Triage and prioritize features for the roadmap and backlog.
- The team was interviewed for a CNN.com series discussing the problem of food deserts while promoting our civic-focused product.

CTDI

Fontana, CA Feb 2013 – Feb 2018 (40 hrs/wk)

Software Engineer

- Full-stack web development for the core product used in quality-control operations. Experienced in JavaScript, HTML, REST APIs, and Oracle / SQL Server databases.
- Communicated and built shared understanding with senior leadership of a long-standing datareporting problem among multiple facilities' operations. Led the design and development of a product that increased reporting efficiency by 93% and removed all possibilities of human error.
 Drove its adoption across 20 facilities and 3 customer programs.
- Gathered and analyzed employee performance data and developed KPI metrics for Fontana operations team used to distinguish and highlight high-performers.

Activities

Hack for LA

Los Angeles, CA Sep 2017 – present

(10 hrs/wk)

Brigade Leader / Product Manager

- Lead, mentor, and organize a community of civic tech enthusiasts as we strategize, design, and build digital products to best serve the people of Los Angeles.
- Provide pro bono tech consulting services for City of Los Angeles, LA County, and local nonprofits.
- The brigade was presented with certificates of excellence by the Los Angeles City Council for its work in civic tech within the community.

Education

University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA)

B.S. Electrical Engineering 2007-2011

Skills

- Lean UX
- User-centered design
- User research
- User testing

- Lean software development
- Data-informed decision-making (DIDM)
- Google Analytics
- Data analysis

- Agile
- Kanban
- Mobile product design
- Design tools: Sketch, Figma, Marvel App